Guide to the Victor F. Germack and Lori Shepard Germack Collection of Photographs of Indians of North America
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Photographic Prints, Series IV; 2.4; (7 boxes)
  - Geographical Surveys West of the 100th Meridian (U.S.)
    - Canon de Chelle (No. 12); Tents of "Camp Beauty" in Canyon de Chelly, Arizona., 1873 (Box 24, Folder 857)
      Printed on mat board: "Geographical Explorations & Surveys West of the 100th Meridian, Expedition of 1873. Under Command of Lieut. Geo. M. Wheeler, Corps of Eng'rs.," and "Walls of the Grand Canon about 1200 feet in height" printed under title.
    - Men in a Gazebo at Hooper's Spring near the Sweetwater River on the Oregon Trail, Natrona County, Wyoming, circa 1873-1878 (Box 21, Folder 858)
      Printed on mat board: "Dept. of the Interior, U.S. Survey of the Territories. Prof. F. V. Hayden in Charge."
  - Gifford, Benjamin Arthur
    - Captain Thomas Simpson, Yakima Indian Man, circa 1895-circa 1905 (Box 7, Folder 859)
    - Captain Thomas Simpson and his Son and Daughter, Yakima Indians, circa 1895-circa 1905 (Box 7, Folder 860)
    - Ida, Woman of Klikitat Indian and European American Ancestry, circa 1895-circa 1905 (Box 7, Folder 861)
    - James Wahpat and his Wife, Wasco Indians, circa 1895-circa 1905 (Box 7, Folder 862)
    - Martin Spedis and his Brother, Klikitat Indian Men, circa 1895-circa 1905 (Box 7, Folder 863)
    - Brother of Matrin Spedis, Klikitat Indian Men, circa 1895-circa 1905 (Box 7, Folder 863)
    - Martin Spedis, Klikitat Indian Man, circa 1895-circa 1905; 2 discrete photographic prints (Box 7, Folder 864)
    - Short Arm (Kangi-Sha-Pa), Yakima Indian Man, circa 1895-circa 1905 (Box 7, Folder 865)
    - Stokin, Man from the Cascade Tribe, circa 1895-circa 1905 (Box 7, Folder 866)
    - Stokin, Man from the Cascade Tribe, and Wa-Bi-Gee, Wasco Indian Man, circa 1895-circa 1905 (Box 7, Folder 867)
    - Stokin, Man from the Cascade Tribe, and Wa-Bi-Gee, Wasco Indian Man (No. 167), circa 1895-circa 1905 (Box 7, Folder 868)
    - Tomelike, Hood River Indian Man, circa 1895-circa 1905 (Box 7, Folder 869)
    - Copy Photograph of a Portrait of Victor Trevitt, circa 1880, a European American Man, Saloon Owner, and Merchant in The Dalles, Oregon, circa 1895-circa 1905 (Box 7, Folder 870)
    - Wa-Bi-Gee, Wasco Indian Man (No. 163), circa 1895-circa 1905 (Box 7, Folder 871)
    - Wa-Bi-Gee, Wasco Indian Man (No. 164), circa 1895-circa 1905 (Box 7, Folder 872)
    - Wa-Bi-Gee, Wasco Indian Man, and an American Indian Boy and Girl (No. 160), circa 1895-circa 1905 (Box 7, Folder 873)
    - Wa-Bi-Gee, Wasco Indian Man, and his Wife, an American Indian Woman, circa 1895-circa 1905 (Box 7, Folder 874)
    - Waptettle, American Indian Woman, circa 1895-circa 1905 (Box 7, Folder 875)
    - Winyah, Yakima Indian Man, circa 1895-circa 1905 (Box 7, Folder 876)
    - Salish Indian Woman (No. 165), circa 1895-circa 1905 (Box 7, Folder 877)
    - Yakima Indian Man Wearing a Hat and West Salmon, an American Indian Man, circa 1895-circa 1905 (Box 7, Folder 878)
    - American Indian Madonna, Oregon, circa 1895-circa 1905 (Box 7, Folder 879)
    - Elderly American Indian Woman, circa 1895-circa 1905; 2 discrete photographic prints (Box 7, Folder 880)
    - American Indian Man (No. 171), circa 1895-circa 1905 (Box 7, Folder 881)
    - American Indian Man, circa 1895-circa 1905 (Box 7, Folder 882)
    - American Indian Man, circa 1895-circa 1905 (Box 7, Folder 883)
    - American Indian Man, circa 1895-circa 1905 (Box 7, Folder 884)
    - American Indian Man, circa 1895-circa 1905 (Box 7, Folder 885)
    - American Indian Man and American Indian Woman, circa 1895-circa 1905 (Box 7, Folder 886)
    - Two American Indian Women, circa 1895-circa 1905 (Box 7, Folder 887)
    - Two American Indian Women, circa 1895-circa 1905 (Box 7, Folder 888)
    - American Indian Woman, circa 1895-circa 1905 (Box 7, Folder 888)
    - Two American Indian Women, Oregon, circa 1895-circa 1905 (Box 7, Folder 889)
    - American Indian Man and Woman, circa 1895-circa 1905 (Box 7, Folder 890)
    - American Indian Man and Woman, circa 1895-circa 1905 (Box 7, Folder 891)
    - Two American Indian Men, Oregon, circa 1895-circa 1905 (Box 7, Folder 892)
    - Three American Indian Men, circa 1895-circa 1905 (Box 7, Folder 893)
    - Elderly American Indian Man and Woman with an American Indian Girl, circa 1895-circa 1905 (Box 7, Folder 894)
    - Two American Indian Men, an American Indian Woman, and American Indian Child, circa 1895-circa 1905 (Box 7, Folder 895)
    - Three American Indian Woman, One Woman Nursing an Infant, an American Indian Boy, and an American Indian Girl, circa 1895-circa 1905 (Box 7, Folder 896)
  - Haynes, Frank Jay
    - Flathead Indian Family, Consisting of a Man, Woman, and Two Boys, in Front of a Tipi in Montana, circa 1880 (Box 7, Folder 897)
      Created for the Northern Pacific Railway
  - Hazeltine, Martin Mason
    - Foot Bridge, Leading to Nevada Fall, After a Snow Storm in July, Yosemite Valley, California, 1868-1870 (Box 7, Folder 898)
      Published by John P. Soule in 1870.
    - Vernal Fall, Yosemite Valley, California, 1868-1870 (Box 7, Folder 899)
  - Hiestand, Joseph G.
    - Cheyenne Canyon, Colorado (No. 98), circa 1890 (Box 7, Folder 900)
    - Canyon in Colorado, circa 1890 (Box 7, Folder 901)
    - United States Signal Station on the Summit of Pikes Peak, Colorado (No. 340), circa 1892 (Box 7, Folder 902)
  - Hileman, Tomar Jacob
    - Heavy Shield, Kainah Indian Man (No. 9558), 1927 May 13 (Box 21, Folder 903)
    - White Wolf, Kainah Indian Man (No. 9546), 1927 May 13 (Box 21, Folder 904)
    - Three Guns, Kainah Indian Man (No. 9548), 1927 May 13 (Box 21, Folder 905)
  - Hillers, John K.
    - From the Top of Zuni, New Mexico, Looking East, 1879 (Box 21, Folder 906)
  - Huffman, Laton Alton
    - Crow Indian Man Scout in Winter Dress-Dancing Costume (No. 50), 1878 (Box 7, Folder 907)
    - Spotted Deer, Teton Indian Man (No. 133), circa 1878 (Box 7, Folder 908)
    - Spotted Eagle, Teton Indian Man (No. 116), 1878 (Box 7, Folder 909)
    - Spotted Fawn, Cheyenne Indian Girl of 13 Years Old (No. 124), 1878 (Box 7, Folder 910)
    - Comenha, Northern Cheyenne Indian Woman, Daughter of Morning Star (also known as Dull Knife, Vóóhéhéve or Tamílapéšni) (No. 120 and No. 59), 1880 (Box 7, Folder 911)
    - Mrs. Bad Gun, Gros Ventre Indian Woman (No. 100), 1880 (Box 7, Folder 912)
  - International Newsreel Corporation
    - Sailor from the USS Sinclair Posed Atop a Totem Pole Near Sitka, Alaska, 1920 August (Box 7, Folder 913)
    - Dog Sled Team at Glacier National Park, Montana, 1924 December (Box 7, Folder 914)
    - American Indian Man, circa 1925 (Box 7, Folder 915)
  - Jackson, William Henry
    - Group of Pawnee Indian Children Attending Boarding School Outside Brick School Building on the Pawnee Reservation in Nebraska (No. 525), 1868 (Box 7, Folder 916)
    - Pike's Peak (No. 608). View of the Gateway Rock Formation (Gate Rock) at Garden of the Gods, Colorado; Pike's Peak in the Distance, circa 1885 (Box 7, Folder 917)
    - Ute Indian Woman, Daughter of Washington, circa 1875 (Box 7, Folder 918)
    - Black Hawk and Winneshiek, Ho-Chunk Indian Men, 1875 (Box 21, Folder 919)
  - Kolb Bros.
    Partnership of Ellsworth Kolb and Emery Kolb at the Grand Canyon, Arizona, 1903-1924.
    - Havasupai Indian Man Standing, Full Figure, Looking at Waterfall, in Arizona, 1913 (Box 21, Folder 920)
    - Hopi Indian Man with Spinning Spindle, Beside Fireplace, 1913 (Box 21, Folder 921)
    - Hopi Indian Woman Corn Grinder (No. 135), 1911 (Box 21, Folder 922)
    - Ki-Kop-Te, Hopi Indian Man, 1913 (Box 21, Folder 923)
  - Lomen Bros.
    Printed by the International Newsreel Corporation.
    Affixed news releases on versos of several prints describe an icebound Nome, as well as a diphtheria epidemic in the city, and efforts to deliver anti-toxin via dog sled.
    - Nome, Alaska, From the Bering Sea Showing the Waterfront and Ice Hummocks (No. 773), 1925 January (Box 7, Folder 924)
    - Ice Hummocks on the Bering Sea near Nome, Alaska (No. 795), 1925 January (Box 7, Folder 925)
    - Dog Sled Team and Man on Ice Hummocks on Trail Between Unalaklut and Nome, Alaska, 1925 February (Box 7, Folder 926)
    - Dog Sled Team and Man near Ice Hummocks on the Bering Sea Near Nome, Alaska, 1925 February (Box 7, Folder 927)
  - Lummis, Charles Fletcher
    - Pueblo of Laguna, New Mexico, 1890 (Box 7, Folder 928)
    - Sun Dance at Cochiti, New Mexico (No. 11), 1888 (Box 7, Folder 929)
    - Pueblo Dwelling, Santo Domingo Pueblo, New Mexico (No. 17), circa 1889 (Box 7, Folder 930)
    - Two Isleta Indian Women at Pueblo of Isleta, New Mexico (No. 39), circa 1889 (Box 7, Folder 931)
    - Reyes Chirina, an Isleta Indian Woman, at Pueblo of Isleta, New Mexico (No. 40), circa 1889 (Box 7, Folder 932)
    - Pueblo of Laguna, New Mexico (No. 50), circa 1889 (Box 7, Folder 933)
    - San José de la Laguna Mission and Convento at the Pueblo of Laguna, New Mexico (No. 54), circa 1889 (Box 7, Folder 934)
    - Three Laguna Indian Women at the Pueblo of Laguna, New Mexico (No. 57), circa 1889 (Box 7, Folder 935)
    - Interior of a Pueblo Home at Zuni, New Mexico (No. 98), circa 1889 (Box 7, Folder 936)
    - Dance at Pueblo of Santa Clara, New Mexico (No. 411), 1889 (Box 7, Folder 937)
    - An Isleta Indian Woman Grinding Corn at Pueblo of Isleta, New Mexico (No. 501), circa 1890 (Box 7, Folder 938)
    - Group of Isleta Indians at Pueblo of Isleta, New Mexico (No. 532), 1890 (Box 7, Folder 939)
    - Pueblo Indian Mother and Daughters (No. 536), 1890 (Box 7, Folder 940)
    - Interior of an Isleta Indian House at Pueblo of Isleta, New Mexico (No. 544), 1890 (Box 7, Folder 941)
    - Isleta Indians Playing Patol at Pueblo of Isleta, New Mexico (No. 562), 1890 (Box 7, Folder 942)
    - An Aboriginal Toilet; Isleta Indians at Pueblo of Isleta, New Mexico (No. 567), 1890 (Box 7, Folder 943)
    - Mrs. Lo, an Isleta Indian Woman, at Pueblo of Isleta, New Mexico (No. 572), 1890 (Box 7, Folder 944)
    - Kitchen in an Isleta Indian House at Pueblo of Isleta, New Mexico (No. 575), 1890 (Box 7, Folder 945)
    - One Hundred and One; an Elderly Isleta Indian Man and Isleta Indian Infant at Pueblo of Isleta, New Mexico (No. 591), 1890 (Box 7, Folder 946)
    - Elderly Tiwa Indians Woman Knitting at Pueblo of Isleta, New Mexico (No. 592), 1890 (Box 7, Folder 947)
    - Tiwa Indian Boy Throwing a Lasso at Pueblo of Isleta, New Mexico (No. 593), 1890 (Box 7, Folder 948)
    - Pueblo Indian Girl at the Pueblo of Laguna, New Mexico (No. 631), 1891 (Box 7, Folder 949)
    - Interior of San José de la Laguna Mission and Convento at the Pueblo of Laguna, New Mexico (No. 636), 1891 (Box 7, Folder 950)
    - South House (Hlaukwima) at Taos Pueblo, New Mexico (No. 700), circa 1891 (Box 7, Folder 951)
    - Taos Indian Foot Race Participants at Taos Pueblo, New Mexico (No. 702), 1889 (Box 7, Folder 952)
    - Old Church and North House (Hlauuma) at Taos Pueblo, New Mexico (No. 703), circa 1891 (Box 7, Folder 953)
    - Maid and Matron; Two Hopi Indian Women at Walpi, Arizona (No. 1406), 1891 (Box 7, Folder 954)
    - Walpi, Arizona, From the North (No. 1407), 1891 (Box 7, Folder 955)
  - Manley, Roger
    - Women Playing Cadil, Navajo Community of Chilchinbeto, Arizona, 1980 (Box 24, Folder 956)
  - Moorhouse, Thomas Leander "Lee"
    Detail photographs from images by Moorhouse and printed circa 1965. Dates given here are for the original Moorhouse images.
    Moorhouse copied the work of other photographers, including Frank La Roche, Frank Palmer, Roland Reed, and Thomas H. Rutter.
    - Young Chief, Umatilla Indian Man, on Horseback, circa 1900 (Box 22, Folder 957-958)
    - Portrait of Chief Joseph or Thunder Rolling Down the Mountain (Hinmuuttu-yalatlat or In Mut Too Yah Lat Lat), Nez Percé Indian Man, 1901 (Box 22, Folder 959)
    - Chief Peo and His Children, Tema Peo and Walter Peo, Umatilla Indians, circa 1900 (Box 22, Folder 960)
    - George Marshall (Cultus), Umatilla Indian Man, circa 1900 (Box 22, Folder 961-962)
      Images depict Marshall wearing a feather bonnet and holding the tomahawk that allegedly killed Marcus Whitman (1802-1847).
    - Charly Whirlwind, Doctor Whirlwind, Chief Sergeant Charley Staplish, or Pat Shamkain, a Cayuse Indian Man, circa 1900-1905 (Box 22, Folder 963-966)
    - Group of Yakima Indian Women, Men, and Children, circa 1900; 2 photographic prints that form a panorama (Box 22, Folder 967)
      Original photograph by Thomas H. Rutter, circa 1900.
      Woman with painted face in the image identified as Ellen or Ella, a Daughter of Shuta-Moni or Shut-a-mo-wani, next to her mother and an infant in a cradleboard.
    - American Indian Men on Horseback on a Mountain Trail, circa 1920 (Box 22, Folder 968)
    - American Indian Man Holding a Rope, circa 1900 (Box 22, Folder 969)
    - American Indian Woman Wrapped in a Pendleton Blanket, circa 1900 (Box 22, Folder 970)
    - American Indian Man Posed Standing and Wearing a Cowboy Outfit with a White Horse in a Town by a Crowd of European American and American Indian Men and Boys, circa 1900 (Box 22, Folder 971)
    - American Indian and European American Children Posed and a European American Woman Teacher in Front of the Umatilla Indian School, Umatilla Indian Reservation, Oregon, circa 1900 (Box 22, Folder 972)
    - Elderly American Indian Woman Cooking, circa 1900 (Box 22, Folder 973)
    - American Indian Man Wearing a Feather Headdress, circa 1900 (Box 22, Folder 974)
    - American Indian Woman and Two American Indian Boys in a Camp with Drying Meat and a Tent, circa 1900 (Box 22, Folder 975)
    - Three American Indian Boys and Two American Indian Girls, circa 1900 (Box 22, Folder 976)
    - Two American Indians Posed Standing and Three American Indians Posed Sitting on the Ground, circa 1900 (Box 22, Folder 977)
    - Cayuse Indian Boy and Girl, Probably the Children of Ida Howlishtehowena, circa 1900 (Box 22, Folder 978)
    - Yakima Indian Woman and Child in Cradleboard, circa 1900 (Box 22, Folder 979)
    - Umatilla Indian Man on Horseback with a Bow and Arrow, circa 1900 (Box 22, Folder 980)
    - American Indian Man Posed Drawing a Bow and Arrow and Wearing a Feather Bonnet, circa 1900 (Box 22, Folder 981)
    - American Indian Man on Horseback, circa 1900 (Box 22, Folder 982)
    - Five Yakima Indian Men with a Drum and Calumet, circa 1903 (Box 22, Folder 983)
      Original photograph by Thomas H. Rutter.
    - American Indian Woman, Identitfied in Negative as Mrs. Reubens, circa 1900 (Box 22, Folder 984)
    - Kalispel Indians on the Pend Oreille River, Washington, circa 1905 (Box 22, Folder 985)
      Original photograph by Frank Palmer.
    - Yakima Indian Maiden, circa 1896 (Box 22, Folder 986)
      Original photograph by Frank La Roche.
    - American Indian Woman and a Crying American Indian Infant in a Cradleboard, circa 1900 (Box 22, Folder 987)
    - American Indian Man Posed Standing and Holding a Rifle, circa 1900 (Box 22, Folder 988)
    - Interior of the Thomas Leander Moorhouse Collection of American Indian Costumes and Artifacts, circa 1900 (Box 22, Folder 989)
    - Sunny Eye, Nez Percé Indian Man, circa 1900 (Box 22, Folder 990)
    - Three Umatilla Indian Women, circa 1900 (Box 22, Folder 991)
    - Group of Yakima Indian Women, Men, and Boys, circa 1903; 2 photographic prints that form a panorama (Box 22, Folder 992)
      Original photograph by Thomas H. Rutter, circa 1900
    - Collage of Photographs of Umatilla Indians, circa 1903 (Box 22, Folder 993)
    - Siksika Indian Men and Women on Horseback, Some with Travois, in Glacier National Park, Montana, circa 1915 (Box 22, Folder 994)
      Original photograph by Roland Reed
  - Nielsen, A. P.
    - Fourteen American Indian Girls at the Santa Fe Indian School in Santa Fe, New Mexico, Upon Their Arrival, 1886 (Box 7, Folder 995)
    - Fourteen American Indian Girls at the Santa Fe Indian School in Santa Fe, New Mexico, One Week After Their Arrival (No. 35), 1886 (Box 7, Folder 996)
  - Morse, Samuel Gay
    - Makah Indian Members of the Baseball Team for Cape Flattery, Washington, circa 1910 (Box 7, Folder 997)
      Identified, left to right, top row: Del Green, Herman Ward, Henry Markishtum, Bill Tyler, Luke Markishtum; second row: George Young Sebastian LaChester, Ralph LaChester; front row: Sam Almer (possibly), Louis Yokum, Charles Swan.
  - Notman, William McFarlane
    - East Side, Mount Carroll and No. 1 Snow Shed on the Canadian Pacific Railway in Glacier National Park, British Columbia, 1887 (Box 7, Folder 998)
  - Parkhurst, T. Harmon
    - Ceremonial Cave High up on Cliff Wall, Frijoles Canyon, New Mexico, circa 1912 (Box 23, Folder 999)
  - Pennington, William M., and Wesley R. Rowland
    - Navajo Indian Maiden and her Flock of Sheep, 1914 (Box 7, Folder 1000)
  - Press Illustrating Service
    - Totem Pole in Front of a Wooden Building, circa 1925 (Box 7, Folder 1001)
    - Totem Pole in Front of a Wooden Building; Base of Pole Marked with Graffiti, "Jesus Save", circa 1925 (Box 7, Folder 1002)
  - Randall, A. Frank
    - Geronimo (Goyaałé, Goyathlay, or Goyahkla), Chiricahua Indian Man, circa 1883 (Box 7, Folder 1003)
  - Rinehart, Frank Albert, and Adolph F. Muhr
    Frank Albert Rinehart (circa 1862-1928) was the official photographer for the United States Indian Congress of the Trans-Mississippi and International Exposition, held in Omaha, Nebraska, between June 1 and October 31, 1898. During the Congress, Rinehart and/or his assistant Adolph F. Muhr (circa 1858-1913) photographed more than 500 individuals and groups representing the estimated thirty-six tribes represented at the Exposition.
    - American Horse or He-Has-A-White-Man's-Horse (Washi-ta-tonga or Wašíčuŋ Thašúŋke), Oglala Indian Man (No. 1003), 1898 (Box 23, Folder 1004)
    - Peatwy Tuck, Sac and Fox Indian Man (No. 1013), 1898 (Box 23, Folder 1005)
    - Grant Richards (Baw-Law-Cos-Chas Richards, Sentali, or Sentele), Tonkawa Indian Man (No. 1057), 1898 (Box 23, Folder 1006)
    - Little Chief (Hachasnacha), Arapaho Indian Man (No. 1116), 1898 (Box 23, Folder 1007)
    - Cloud Man or James Garfield (Mahpiya Itancan), Assiniboine Indian Man (No. 1121), 1898 (Box 23, Folder 1008)
    - Wolf Robe (Honii-Wotoma, Honih Elwoomah, Honehevotoomahe, Tsitsistas, or Suhtai), Cheyenne Indian Man (No. 1130), 1898 (Box 23, Folder 1009)
    - Wife of Jospeh Street, Ho-Chunk Indian Woman (No. 1131), 1898 (Box 23, Folder 1010)
    - Daniel Hollow Horn Bear, The Bone, or Bone (Mato He Hlogeca, Mato He Oklogeca, Matho-Hexaloketca, Hu-Hu-Lo, or Hoo-Hoo), Teton Indian Man (No. 1153), 1898 (Box 23, Folder 1011)
    - Gentle Bird, Salish Indian Woman (No. 1387), 1898 (Box 23, Folder 1012)
    - Cleaver Warden, Nephew of Powder Face, Arapaho Indian Man (No. 1392), 1898 (Box 23, Folder 1013)
      Identified by a caption in the negative as Yellow Magpie.
    - Wife of Juan Amigo, Pima Indian Woman (No. 1439), 1898 (Box 23, Folder 1014)
    - Four Kiowa Indian Men Posed on Horseback and Chief White Man (Tsayaditl-ti, Ta-Ka-I-Tai-Di, Da-Kana-Dit-Ta-I, Tsayaditlti, or Takaitaide), a Kiowa Indian Man Posed Standing (No. 1515), 1898 (Box 23, Folder 1015)
    - Stars Come Out, Oglala Indian Man (No. 1516), 1898 (Box 23, Folder 1016)
    - Eagle Shirt, Oglala Indian Man (No. 1532), 1898 (Box 23, Folder 1017)
    - Susie Shot In The Eye, Oglala Indian Woman (No. 1541), 1898 (Box 23, Folder 1018)
  - Russell, Andrew J.
    - Exterior group portrait of officials gathered at Fort Sanders near Laramie, Wyoming, during the summer of 1868, which include Ulysses S. Grant, William Tecumseh Sherman, Philip H. Sheridan, and Sidney Dillon, a director of the Union Pacific Railroad Company. (Box 23, Folder 1019)
    - Hall's Cut, Eight Miles East of Sherman Station, Wyoming, 1868-1869 (Box 23, Folder 1020)
    - Valley of the Little Laramie River, 1868-1869 (Box 23, Folder 1021)
  - Savage, Charles Roscoe
    - Royal Gorge, Grand Canon of the Arkansas, Denver and Rio Grande Railway, 1880-1886 (Box 7, Folder 1022)
  - Shindler, A. Zeno
    - Samuel Garland, Choctaw Indian Man (No. 94), 1869 (Box 7, Folder 1023)
    - Allen Wright, Choctaw Indian Man (No. 96), 1869 (Box 7, Folder 1024)
    - Family of George Washington Stidman, Sr., Mixed Blood Creek Indians (No.107), 1869 (Box 7, Folder 1025)
      From left to right, George Washington Stidman, Jr.; George Washington Stidman, Sr.; Sarah C. Thornbury Stidham holding Orlando Stidman; and Georgianna "Annie" Stidman.
    - Georgianna "Annie" Stidman, Mixed Blood Creek Indian Girl (No.105), 1869 (Box 7, Folder 1026)
    - Lightning or Henry Clay (Che-Po-Qua or Che-Po-Swa), Ottawa Indian Man, 1869 (Box 23, Folder 1027)
  - Taber, Isaac W.
    - Interior of an American Indian Hut, Yakutat Bay, Alaska. American Indian Wounded in a Bear Fight (No. 4702), circa 1889 (Box 23, Folder 1028)
  - Taylor, James E.
    - Eagle That Scares (Wanbdi Wanapeya), Yanktonai Indian Man, circa 1885 (Box 7, Folder 1029)
  - Trager, George E.
    - Body of Medicine Man, Taken at the Battle of Wounded Knee, South Dakota (No. 2), 1891 January (Box 7, Folder 1030)
  - Ulke, Henry
    - Spotted Tail (Sinte-Galeska, Cin-Te-Gi-Le-Ska, or Tshin-Ta-Ge-Las-Kah), a Brulé Indian Man, 1877 (Box 7, Folder 1031)
  - Vroman, Adam Clark
    - Buttes, Arizona or New Mexico (No. 570), circa 1900 (Box 7, Folder 1032)
    - Snake Dance of the Hopi Indians at Walpi, Arizona (No. 575), circa 1900 (Box 7, Folder 1033)
  - Whitney, Joel Emmons
    - The Foremost Sitter (Naw-Gaw-Nab), Ojibwa Indian Man (No. 85), circa 1863 (Box 7, Folder 1034)
  - Whitney, Joel Emmons, and Charles A. Zimmerman
    - Beautiful Night or Good Night Woman (Han-ye-tu was-te or Hanyetu-Washte-Win), Mdewakanton Indian Woman, 1862 (Box 7, Folder 1035)
  - Unidentified Photographers, Copy Photographs
    Photographs copied by unidentified photographers, although in some cases the photographer of the original copied image is known.
    - Portraits of Modoc Indian Men Involved in the Modoc War of 1872-1873 in California Originally Photographed by Louis Herman Heller
      Captain Jack and Schonchin John were hanged at Fort Klamath, Oregon, on October 3, 1873, for the murders of Major General Edward Richard Sprigg Canby and Reverend Eleazer Thomas during a peace conference on April 11, 1873.
      - Captain Jack (Kintpuash), Modoc Indian Man, circa 1895 (Box 7, Folder 1036)
      - Schonchin John, Modoc Indian Man, circa 1895 (Box 7, Folder 1037)
      - Scarface Charley, Modoc Indian Man, circa 1895 (Box 7, Folder 1038)
        Inscription in the negative mistakenly states that Scarface Charley was hanged at Fort Klamath, Oregon, on October 3, 1873.
    - Copy Photograph of Princess Angeline (Lushootseed, Kikisoblu, Kick-is-om-lo, or Wewick), a Suquamish Indian Woman and Daughter of Chief Seattle, circa 1900-1905 (Box 7, Folder 1039)
      Original photograph created by Edward Sheriff Curtis in 1896.
  - Unidentified Photographers
    - Mount Shasta from Edgewood, California, circa 1875 (Box 7, Folder 1040)
    - Beacon Rock (also known as Castle Rock), Columbia River, Washington (No. 94), circa 1875 (Box 7, Folder 1041)
    - Mount Hood, Oregon, and The Dalles of the Columbia River (No. 62), circa 1875 (Box 7, Folder 1042)
    - Above the Clouds; A Scene On the Summit (No. 400), circa 1875 (Box 7, Folder 1043)
    - Group of American Indians Drying Fish By a River in California, circa 1880 (Box 23, Folder 1044)
      Mounted on an album sheet. Two photographs on the verso depict the residence of G. B. Williams in Sacramento, California.
    - Overview of a Quarry or Mine Operation with Men and Mules, circa 1880 (Box 23, Folder 1045)